# MANU DWIVEDI

manu29.d@gmail.com | manu29d.github.io

### **PROFILE**

I have about 6 years of experience working with many growth stage and established startups. I'm experienced in developing and maintaining scalable, extensible and reliable products. I believe myself to be highly analytical, empathetic and a curious team player. I love to teach and learn something everyday.

### **SKILLS**

RUBY ON RAILS	REACT	GIT	CI/CD
POSTGRESQL	ANGULAR	DOCKER	AGILE
MONGODB	NODE.JS	VIM	D3JS
TDD/BDD	BACKBONEJS	GOOGLE CHARTS	GIS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, CURVE TOMORROW - MAR 2017 - APR 2019

- Used Rails to build an API that recommends sleep/wake times for nurses
- Used Rails API and Angular micro-services to provide recommendations and manage patient bookings for the deaf community
- Used Rails API and React frontend to follow decision tree of doctor's diagnosis and recommend next treatments for a rare eye disease
- Refactor CI/CD pipeline to improve build times by 60%
- Set standards and build Rails API base to be used company wide on other projects
- Taught, proposed and enforced Git workflows for all teams
- Use RSpec, Capybara/Cucumber, Chromedriver for automated testing with 100% coverage for all projects

## FREELANCE CONSULTANT, MULTIPLE PROJECTS - JAN 2016 - MAR 2017

- Kingfisher #GoodTimes Use node.js, socket.io and jQuery to control video playback, orientation and audio on the computer using the phone
- Proton IoT Use PHP, node.js, MQTT, Google Charts and jQuery to parse data from water dispensing stations and generate visualisations
- Paintcollar Use Angular, node.js, MongoDB to build a product creation engine which can overlay graphic design to merchandising templates in real time
- 3LOQ Use node.js, Angular D3 to make monitoring visualisation for big data and ML pipelines (Ganglia, Talend and other services)
- Use python to package and deploy production applications
- Use D3, jQuery to make visualisation engine to convert given arbitrary excel into flow graphs
- Use CitusDB, Linode to deploy a cluster to the cloud

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER 12, TALENTICA SOFTWARE** – SEP 2014 - JAN 2016

- Use Angular to build video editing screen for a SaaS offering
- Use BackboneJS, Google Maps, GeoJSON to build a GIS based app for real estate analytics visualisation
- Consulting Backbone/Javascript expert for existing investment management portal
- Use Rails, Haml, Bootstrap, Rspec to build and debug features for a local events knowledge engine

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER, KREATIO SOFTWARE - JUN 2013 - SEP 2014

- Use Rails, jQuery to build and end to end solution for teaching using a smart board
- Use Rails, jQuery to build and debug author's publishing CMS (used by Business Insider etc)
- Gitlab Deploy custom white label solution on the in-house cloud infrastructure
- Conducted multiple training sessions on ruby, rails and git

## **ACOMPLISHMENTS**

- Conducted corporate training in Ruby on Rails for Welnvest, 2019
- Conducted a workshop on git for the Computer Society of India, 2019
- Industry Mentor for teams in Smart India Hackathon, 2018 and 2019
- Second Runner-up, IBM-SwissRe Hackathon, 2016

### **EDUCATION**

## NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, TIRUCHIRAPPALLI - B.TECH, 2013

### CONTACT

manu29.d@gmail.com | manu29d.github.io